A Guide to the Papers of Joseph Carrington Cabell Relating to the Founding of the University of Virginia,
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1822 January 21, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 238-239. (Box-folder 1:91)
  Funds for the University. Estimate of revenue from the Literary Fund. References to John Bowyer, Chapman Johnson, and Charles Fenton Mercer.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1822 February 3, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 240-241. (Box-folder 1:92)
  Funds for the University. The Kentucky Mission. States' Rights. References to Samuel Blackburn, Thomas Griffin, Chapman Johnson, and Richard Morris.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1822 February 11, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 242-244. (Box-folder 1:93)
  Funds for the University. The Literary Fund. References to James Breckenridge, [Charles?] Cocke, Chapman Johnson, Thomas Miller, and Richard Morris.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1822 February 25, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 244-245. (Box-folder 1:94)
  Funds for the University. References to John Bowyer, Chapman Johnson, Richard Morris, Samuel Taylor, and David Watson.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Williamsburg, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1822 March 6, ALS. 7 pp Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed (in part): Cabell 245-251. (Box-folder 1:95)
  Failure to pass various bills to provide funds for the University. Reports of extravagance in construction of the buildings. Attack on the Literary Fund based on the waste of the Primary School Fund. References to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough, Samuel Blackburn, John Bowyer, Mr. Clay, Thomas Griffin, Chapman Johnson, Richard Morris, and David Watson.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Williamsburg, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1822 March 10, ALS 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 251-254. (Box-folder 1:96)
  Meeting of the Board of Visitors. Funds for the University. Convinced that all buildings should be completed to give favorable impression. Incidental effects of the move to shift the capital from Richmond to Staunton. Attitude of the Federalist Party. References to Wilson J. Cary, George Crump, Thomas Griffin, Chapman Johnson, James Madison, and John Tyler.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Edgewood, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1822 October 3, ALS. 1 pp. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Endorsed by T. J. Printed: Cabell 254-255. (Box-folder 1:97)
  Illness prevents attendance at the Board of Visitors meeting. Auditing of the University's accounts by Martin Dawson. References to John Hartwell Cocke.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1822 December 19, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed Cabell 255-257. (Box-folder 1:98)
  Funds for the University. Literary Fund finances very unfavorable. Cabell's health improved. Glad T. J.'s wound improving. References to Wilson J. Cary, David S. Garland, William F. Gordon, Chapman Johnson, Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr., [William Cabell] Rives, and Judge St. George Tucker.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1822 December 23, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 257-259. (Box-folder 1:99)
  Cost of building the library estimated by James Dinsmore. Funds for the University. Purchase of books and apparatus. Settlement of the Proctor's accounts. References to John Bowyer, Alexander Garrett, William F. Gordon, James Hunter, George Loyall, and [William Cabell] Rives.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1822 December 30, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Partly printed: Cabell 263-265. (Box-folder 1:100)
  Funds for the University. Cost of the library. Error in the Proctor's accounts. References to Briscoe G. Baldwin, John Bowyer, Wilson J. Cary, John Hartwell Cocke, Peter M. Daniel, David S. Garland, William F. Gordon, Chapman Johnson, Daniel Sheffey, Allen Taylor, and Henry E. Watkins.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 January 9, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 265-266. (Box-folder 1:101)
  Funds for the University. University's popularity shown in elections in Mecklenburg, Lunenburg, Brunswick, Greenville, Henrico, Norfolk, and Essex counties. References to Mr. Clopton, James Hunter, Arthur Lee, and Addison Powell.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 January 23, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 268-270. (Box-folder 1:102)
  Funds for the University and for colleges and primary schools throughout the state. Question of moving the capital from Richmond. References to Hampden-Sydney College, William F. Gordon, [William Cabell] Rives, and Samuel Taylor.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 February 3, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 272-273. (Box-folder 1:103)
  Meeting of the Board of Visitors. Loan bill for the University secure. Mr. Brockenbrough's accounts. References to Philip Doddridge and Thomas Griffin.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 February 5, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 274. (Box-folder 1:104)
  Passage of the University Bill. References to William F. Gordon, Chapman Johnson, and George Loyall.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 February 11, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 274-277. (Box-folder 1:105)
  No attention paid to James Oldham's charges against Arthur Brockenbrough. Chapman Johnson's failure to attend meetings of Board of Visitors. University finances. Application from Dr. Tones, formerly of the College of William and Mary, for the chemistry chair at the University of Virginia. References to Briscoe Baldwin, John Bowyer, Philip Doddridge, David S. Garland, William F. Gordon, George Loyall, Daniel Sheffey, Allen Taylor, and Joseph Watkins.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Williamsburg, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 February 26, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 277-278. (Box-folder 2:1)
  Law regarding seats on the Board of Visitors. Contracts for the library should be for a definite amount. References to Chapman Johnson and John Augustine Smith.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Williamsburg, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 March 24, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 280-282. (Box-folder 2:2)
  Contracts for the library. Funds for the purchase of books and apparatus. References to John Hartwell Cocke and Chapman Johnson.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Edgewood, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 June 24, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Another copy: 3 pp. File draft. Endorsed by Cabell. Cabell Papers. (Box-folder 2:3)
  Requesting T. J.'s advice on plan of jail for Nelson County.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Edgewood, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 July 18, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. (Box-folder 2:4)
  Thanking T. J. for his aid in planning the Nelson County jail. References to Mr. Crawford, Mr. Peck, and William Philips.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Edgewood, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 August 6, ALS. 5 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Enclosure: AD. 2 pp. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Deposited by Philip B. Campbell. (Box-folder 2:5)
  Selection of the site of the Nelson County jail. Details of its plan. References to Arthur Brockenbrough, William Cosby, Mr. Crawford, Mr. Nelson, John Perry, William Phillips. Enclosure: memorandum of the contract made 29 July 1823 between Robert Rives, Joseph C. Cabell, and Thomas Massie, Jr., for the court of Nelson County, and William B. Phillips, who agrees to build the jail. Contract refers to Jefferson's plan.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Edgewood, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 October 27, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Partly printed: Cabell 282-283. (Box-folder 2:6)
  Coffey's and Roscoe's books on prisons. Unable to find the Oxford and Cambridge Guide. New purchase of land will make it necessary to withdraw from the Senate.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 November 22, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 284. (Box-folder 2:7)
  Personal affairs delay his attending Assembly meetings. Returns Roscoe's work on prisons. University bill to be pushed by James Breckenridge and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 December 3, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 285. (Box-folder 2:8)
  Bill to remove the University debt. References to Colonel Boyd, William F. Gordon, James Pleasants, and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1823 December 29, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 286. (Box-folder 2:9)
  Funds for the University. References to Thomas Miller and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 January 26, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 287-288. (Box-folder 2:10)
  Funds for the University. Purchase of books. Reference to Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 January 29, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Partly printed: Cabell 288-290. (Box-folder 2:11)
  Passage of the University bill. Funds for purchase of library and apparatus. Recommending Claude Crozet as professor of mathematics and Dabney Carr as professor of law. Mentions Alexander Garrett.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 February 19, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 293-294. (Box-folder 2:12)
  Logrolling attempt: University bill and the bill to recharter the Farmer's Bank. References to James Breckenridge, Alexander Garrett, William F. Gordon, and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 March 7, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Partly printed: Cabell 294-296. (Box-folder 2:13)
  Funds for the University from the debt due Virginia from the Federal government. Francis Walker Gilmer's scheme of professorships. References to James Barbour, William F. Gordon, [George?] Hay, Chapman Johnson, James Madison, and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Williamsburg, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 March 17, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 296-299. (Box-folder 2:14)
  Complete victory of the friends of the University in the Assembly. Downfall of William and Mary seems certain. Suggests hiring of certain of the William and Mary faculty: John A. Smith, Mr. Campbell, James B. Rogers, and James Semple. References to John Bowyer, James Breckenridge, Alexander Garrett, William F. Gordon, Chapman Johnson, George Loyall, James Madison, and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Washington, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 April 1, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 299-301. (Box-folder 2:15)
  Attempt to get recognition of the University's claim to money owed Virginia by the United States. Monroe's recommendation of [James G.?] Percival and [John] Torrey for the University faculty. References to James Barbour, William H. Crawford, Chapman Johnson, and William Wirt.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell. Edgewood, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 April 8, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 301-302. (Box-folder 2:16)
  Returning a horse loaned by T. J. Reference to Col. John Coles and to Mr. Maclure.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Bremo, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 April 16, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 303-304. (Box-folder 2:17)
  Agreeing to the engagement of the anatomical professor from Europe. Pleased to see the number of foreign professors is to be limited. Note by John Hartwell Cocke: "I concur with Mr. Cabell in the above."
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Williamsburg, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 May 5, ALS. 4 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 305-308. (Box-folder 2:18)
  Attitude of the University toward the possible removal of the College of William and Mary from Williamsburg to Richmond. Views on the subject held by William Armistead, Colonel Bassett, Chancellor Brown, [John B.?] Clopton, Dr. Charles Everett, N. Faulcon, Dr. Galt of Williamsburg, [James M.?] Garrett, Thomas Griffin, Mr. Johnson of Williamsburg, George Loyall, Thomas Macon, Bishop Moore, Hugh Nelson, Mr. Nicholas, Brazure W. Pryor, Archibald Ritchie, Judge James Semple, Mr. Scott, John W. Sourell, L. W. Tazewell, and John Tyler.
- James Madison, Montpellier, to Thomas Jefferson. 1824 May 20, L. 1 pp. Copy by J. C. Cabell. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 313; B of R IV 53 (MS. in DLC). (Box-folder 2:19)
  Urging that the friends of the University of Virginia be passive in regard to the removal of William and Mary from Williamsburg to Richmond, Petersburg, or the western part of the state.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Warminster, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 June 13, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 314-315. (Box-folder 2:20)
  Illness of Mrs. [St. George] Tucker prevents his visiting T. J. at Monticello and the Madisons at Montpellier. Removal of William and Mary to Richmond.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 December 17, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 316-318. (Box-folder 2:21)
  Cabell's business at Corotoman. Assembly politics with respect to the bill to move the College of William and Mary to Richmond and funds for the University. References to George Blaettermann, Francis T. Brooke, John Bowyer, William Brockenbrough, John Coalter, James M. Garnett, George Hay, Chapman Johnson, Mr. Leigh, Judge Marshall, James Madison, Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr., and Robert B. Taylor.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 December 21, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 318-320. (Box-folder 2:22)
  Decision to vote against the bill to remove William and Mary to Richmond. Medical education at the University. References to Chapman Johnson and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1824 December 31, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Partly printed: Cabell 324-327. (Box-folder 2:23)
  Differences of opinion between Jefferson and Madison regarding the removal of the College of William and Mary to Richmond. Funds for the University. References to John Bowyer, Judge Dabney Carr, Francis W. Gilmer, William F. Gordon, George Loyall, Mr. Nicholas, James Pleasants, Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr., James Semple, John A. Smith, George Tucker, and John Tyler.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 January 6, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 328-329. (Box-folder 2:24)
  Letter from George Tucker regarding a teaching position at the University. Application from Mr. Kidd for the position of professor of ethics. Bill for removal of William and Mary to Richmond to be rejected. Funds for the University. References to James Barbour, William F. Gordon, Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr., James Madison, and Judge James Semple.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 January 16, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Partly printed: Cabell 332-333. (Box-folder 2:25)
  Request that T. J. prepare a bill to prevent removal of William and Mary College to Richmond. Clergy, Richmond, and the Federalists all united in favor of removal.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 January 28, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 336. (Box-folder 2:26)
  Removal of William and Mary to Richmond. Articles in the Whig on the funds of William and Mary and the decision of the Court of Appeals in the case of Bracken and the College. References to Alexander Garrett and John A. Smith.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 January 30, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 336-337. (Box-folder 2:27)
  News of Ship Competitor. Requests authorities to support the division of William and Mary's money. Mentions Dartmouth College case.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 February 3, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 337-338. (Box-folder 2:28)
  Publication of a letter from T. J. to help prevent removal of the College of William and Mary to Richmond. Consideration of Francis W. Gilmer and Chancellor [St. George] Tucker for the law chair at the University. Suggests the professor of law be also given a small chancery district. References to Servant Jones and Richard Morris.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 February 7, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Partly printed: Cabell 341-342. (Box-folder 2:29)
  Defeat of plan to remove William and Mary to Richmond. Plan for a general education system.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 February 11, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Partly printed: Cabell 343-345. (Box-folder 2:30)
  Defeat of the bill to remove William and Mary to Richmond. Delay in arrival of the University faculty. T. J.'s resolutions relative to primary schools. Expresses disapproval of a constitutional convention for Virginia. Opposition to Cabell in his senatorial district. References to John Bowyer, Judge Francis T. Brooke, Col. Benjamin Cabell, John Hartwell Cocke, David S. Garland, William F. Gordon, George Loyall, and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 February 11, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 346. (Box-folder 2:31)
  Funds for the University from interest claim of the Commonwealth of Virginia. References to George Loyall and Littleton W. Tazewell.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 February 18, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 346-347. (Box-folder 2:32)
  Arrival of the University faculty. Meeting of the Board of Visitors. References to Chapman Johnson, Francis Gilmer, George Loyall, and John Hartwell Cocke.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 February 21, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 347. (Box-folder 2:33)
  aculty positions offered to [Henry St. George?] Tucker and to George Tucker. References to Judge John Coalter and [St. George] Tucker.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Norfolk, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 May 6, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 351. (Box-folder 2:34)
  Approves purchase of John M. Perry's land for the University.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Norfolk, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 May 25, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 353-354. (Box-folder 2:35)
  Approves choice of William A. G. Dade for the law chair. Splendid prospects for the University. Greetings from Mr. Maclure in Paris.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1825 December 7, ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 357-358. (Box-folder 2:36)
  Death of his brother-in-law, Dr. Carter, prevents his attendance at Board of Visitors' meeting. New regulations at the University. References to John Hartwell Cocke, Thomas Cooper, Chapman Johnson, George Loyall, and [George] Tucker.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1826 January 30, ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Partly printed: Cabell 360361. (Box-folder 2:37)
  Conference between George Loyall, Chapman Johnson, and Cabell regarding delay in the appointment of a law professor. Action regarding the William and Mary Bill. Conference regarding T. J.'s debts. References to Judge Francis T. Brooke, Judge Dabney Carr, Judge John Coalter, Judge John W. Green, and John T. Lemare.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1826 February 3, ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 362. (Box-folder 2:38)
  Meeting of T. J.'s friends in support of the lottery. David S. Garland's bill for educational funds.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1826 February 8, ALS. 4 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Partly printed: Cabell 367-369. (Box-folder 2:39)
  T. J.'s plan for location of colleges throughout the state better than that of David S. Garland. Motion made by George Loyall regarding T. J.'s lottery.
- Joseph Carrington Cabell, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson, Monticello. 1826 February 10, ALS. 4 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photocopy. #2791. Original in Papers of Thomas Jefferson. Printed: Cabell 370-372. (Box-folder 2:40)